Austin Buhler

Encinitas, CA | (949) 614-6943 | austinbuhler@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Full Stack Software Developer

Software engineer experienced in C#/.NET, JavaScript, Python and Ruby on Rails with a background in corporate finance. Analytical, strategically minded leader with a demonstrated ability of driving business objectives into results. Efficient and resourceful problem solver with an innate curiosity and an entrepreneurial spirit who thrives in a fast-paced team environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C# | .NET | JavaScript | SQL | Python | Ruby | Rails | Node.js | React | Redux | Power BI | D3 | jQuery | Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PetcoFull Stack Software Developer

San Diego, CA

Apr 2021 - Present

- Designed and implemented a Project Management Tracker, integrating with external Construction Management System through 3rd party API, enabling construction stakeholders to actively manage and track changes to project timelines
 - Extended functionality and revamped user interfaces within internal Real Estate GIS Mapping & Deal Tracking C#/.NET web application, more than doubling daily active users
 - Automated financial reporting models and metrics built in Excel with Python, synthesizing with data from Snowflake Data Warehouse into MS SQL Server
 - Centralized and homogenized Real Estate and Construction data in a Power BI dashboard, bringing increased visibility and accountability to critical KPIs
 - Created REST APIs in C# to deliver consolidated financial metrics to be consumed by custom D3 visuals
 - Optimized data architecture, SQL views and added application level caching improving page load times by over 90%
 - Introduced an admin interface with an error logging dashboard, email notifications and a user permissions manager
 - Created and maintained technical documentation of critical data structures and a data glossary for end users

Siggi's Dairy

New York, NY

Senior Manager, FP&A

Apr 2020 – Aug 2020

- Prepared and led monthly financial presentations delivering actionable insights and driving strategic decisions alongside key internal and external stakeholders
- Developed and actively managed rolling forecast, identifying key risks and opportunities to budget financials

Manager, FP&A

Apr 2019 – Mar 2020

- Spearheaded \$200MM+ annual budget and operating plan, facilitating cross-functional collaboration
- Served as ERP Systems Manager, ensuring data integrity, improving reports/processes and actively managing 50+ EDI trading partners
- Collaborated with intercompany partners and external consultants to ensure all system functional requirements were met as part of freight consolidation project leading to \$5MM+ in savings

Senior Financial Analyst

Jan 2018 – Mar 2019

- Drove and executed financial reporting integration efforts into Hyperion and TM1 following international acquisition
- Developed a fully automated Daily Sales Dashboard, increasing efficiency and enabling real-time analysis of business trends and KPIs

Financial Analyst

Aug 2016 - Dec 2017

- Managed monthly COGS analysis, inventory reconciliation & valuation with our 3PL provider and quarterly co-manufacturer audits that led to \$150K+ in rebates
- Supported transition from Quickbooks to Microsoft NAV serving as the order-to-cash subject matter expert

PROJECTS

ProjectSocial - FrontEnd | BackEnd | Website

A social app connecting New Yorkers by enabling them to host and attend events at public parks in their local neighborhood. This is a Single-Page Application built with React/Redux, PostgreSQL and a RESTful Rails API.

- Utilized React Hooks and Redux for state management as well as React Router for Client-Side Routing
- Normalized store shape to ensure a single-source of truth and increased application performance
- Integrated parks' data from NYC's Open Data Portal with Google Maps API to plot all public parks and their activities
- Leveraged WebSockets to ensure a real-time event news feed for seamless user communication and coordination

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Software Engineering Immersive; Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails

Dec 2020

Southern Methodist University, Cox School of Business

Bachelor of Business Administration, Finance

Dallas, TX May 2016